<story-context id=".bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>3</epicId>
    <storyId>2</storyId>
    <title>Generate Cover Letter</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>lørdag 13. desember 2025</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>C:\Users\jenny\Documents\SG-Oslo-Best\docs\sprint-artifacts\3-2-generate-cover-letter.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>logged-in student user</asA>
    <iWant>to click a "Generate" button to create a cover letter</iWant>
    <soThat>I can receive an AI-drafted letter tailored to the job</soThat>
    <tasks>- [ ] **Backend:** Create `POST /api/v1/generation` endpoint. (AC: #3)
    - [ ] Endpoint should accept user's CV data, job advertisement, and optional instructions.
    - [ ] Service layer should call the Gemini API with the provided data.
    - [ ] Endpoint should return the generated cover letter text.
- [ ] **Frontend:** Implement the "Generate" button logic. (AC: #1, #2, #4)
    - [ ] On click, disable the input fields.
    - [ ] Display the "Generation Status Indicator" component.
    - [ ] Call the `POST /api/v1/generation` endpoint using React Query.
    - [ ] On success, hide the status indicator and display the returned text.
    - [ ] On error, hide the status indicator and show an error message.
- [ ] **Testing:** Add Playwright E2E test for the generation flow. (AC: #1, #2, #4)
    - [ ] Test that input fields are disabled during generation.
    - [ ] Test that the loading indicator is displayed.
    - [ ] Mock the API response and test that the generated text is displayed correctly.</tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>1.  Given I have provided a job advertisement and clicked "Generate", when the generation process begins, then all input fields are temporarily disabled.
2.  And the UI shows the "Generation Status Indicator" (Story 3.8).
3.  And the backend receives the necessary data, integrates with the Gemini API, and returns the generated text.
4.  When the generation is complete, the generated cover letter text is returned to the frontend.</acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Executive Summary</section>
        <snippet>CVAI Turbo is a web application designed to help university and college students generate tailored cover letters using an AI (Gemini). The core functionality involves users providing their CV information and a job description, upon which the AI generates a customized cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Product Scope - MVP - Cover Letter Generation</section>
        <snippet>The MVP will focus on delivering the core functionality to generate customized cover letters. Key features include: Cover Letter Generation: A "Generate" button triggers the AI (third-party LLM) to produce a customized cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Functional Requirements - Cover Letter Generation</section>
        <snippet>FR-3.3 [MVP] The system shall generate a customized cover letter based on the user's CV, job advertisement, and instructions. FR-3.4 [MVP] The system shall display the generated cover letter to the user in plain text.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Non-Functional Requirements - Integration</section>
        <snippet>The application will integrate with a Gemini family Large Language Model (LLM) via its API for the core cover letter generation functionality.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Executive Summary</section>
        <snippet>CVAI Turbo is a web application designed to help university and college students generate tailored cover letters using an AI (Gemini). The core functionality involves users providing their CV information and a job description, upon which the AI generates a customized cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Core Technologies</section>
        <snippet>Frontend Framework: Next.js (with React), Backend Framework: FastAPI, Database & Authentication: Supabase, API Communication (Frontend): React Query (TanStack Query).</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Decision Summary</section>
        <snippet>API Communication (Frontend): React Query (TanStack Query) for data fetching and caching. Testing Strategy: Jest for unit/component tests; Playwright for end-to-end (E2E) tests.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Project Structure</section>
        <snippet>backend/app/api/v1/generation.py, backend/services/</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Epic to Architecture Mapping</section>
        <snippet>Epic 3: Core Cover Letter Generation. Primary Code Location(s): frontend/app/dashboard/, backend/app/api/v1/generation.py, backend/services/.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Integration Points</section>
        <snippet>The primary integration point between the frontend and backend is a versioned REST API. The Next.js frontend will use React Query to communicate with the FastAPI backend.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Security Architecture</section>
        <snippet>API Keys: Securely managed using environment variables (e.g., Vercel secrets) for third-party services (Gemini API, Resend API).</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <section>Performance Considerations</section>
        <snippet>Backend (FastAPI): High-performance Python web framework, designed for speed. Stateless design of API endpoints to facilitate horizontal scaling and load balancing.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Executive Summary</section>
        <snippet>CVAI Turbo is a web application designed to help university and college students overcome the difficulty of writing tailored cover letters. Our solution provides an AI-powered tool that takes a user's CV information and a job description, and automatically generates a relevant, high-quality cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>User Journey Flows - Cover Letter Generation</section>
        <snippet>The flow incorporates guiding button states, versioned regeneration for comparison, and clear, multi-layered feedback on save actions. The right column is replaced by a loading indicator and then the generated cover letter text.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Component Library - Custom Components - Generation Status Indicator</section>
        <snippet>Purpose: To act as a responsive progress indicator during the AI generation process. Content: loading spinner. Periodically, the text message "Please give us an A" will appear alongside it.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>UX Pattern Decisions - Feedback Patterns - Loading Feedback</section>
        <snippet>Spinner for short waits, and Skeleton loaders for longer waits or content areas. Usage: Spinner for actions like "Generate Cover Letter" (using custom "Generation Status Indicator").</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>ibe160 UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Responsive Design &amp; Accessibility - Accessibility Strategy - ARIA Requirements for Custom Components</section>
        <snippet>For the "Generation Status Indicator": The region where the cover letter appears must have `aria-live="polite"`. While the loading spinner is active, it should be accompanied by visually hidden text.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/epics.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Epics &amp; Stories</title>
        <section>Epic 3: Core Cover Letter Generation</section>
        <snippet>Goal: Deliver the primary value of the application by enabling students to generate a customized cover letter based on their CV and a job description. Scope: Implement the UI for inputting a job ad and instructions, the backend logic to integrate with the Gemini API, and the display of the generated cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/epics.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Epics &amp; Stories</title>
        <section>Story 3.2: Generate Cover Letter</section>
        <snippet>As a logged-in student user, I want to click a "Generate" button to create a cover letter, so that I can receive an AI-drafted letter tailored to the job. Technical Notes: The frontend will send the user's CV data, job advertisement, and optional instructions to a POST /api/v1/generation endpoint. The backend service will then interact with the Gemini API to generate the cover letter.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/epics.md</path>
        <title>CVAI Turbo - Epics &amp; Stories</title>
        <section>New Story 3.8: Implement Generation Status Indicator Component</section>
        <snippet>As a developer, I want to create the "Generation Status Indicator" component, so that users are kept engaged and informed during the AI generation process with a loading spinner and specified text. Technical Notes: This is a reusable UI component to be built with React/TypeScript and styled with Tailwind CSS.</snippet>
      </artifact>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <artifact>
        <path>frontend/app/dashboard/</path>
        <kind>directory</kind>
        <symbol>N/A</symbol>
        <lines>N/A</lines>
        <reason>Location for frontend UI components related to the cover letter generation page.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>frontend/lib/</path>
        <kind>directory</kind>
        <symbol>N/A</symbol>
        <lines>N/A</lines>
        <reason>Location for frontend API call logic, including React Query setup.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>backend/app/api/v1/generation.py</path>
        <kind>file</kind>
        <symbol>N/A</symbol>
        <lines>N/A</lines>
        <reason>New file for the FastAPI endpoint that handles cover letter generation.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>backend/app/services/</path>
        <kind>directory</kind>
        <symbol>N/A</symbol>
        <lines>N/A</lines>
        <reason>Location for backend service logic that integrates with the Gemini API.</reason>
      </artifact>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <nodejs>
        <package>next: ^16.0.10</package>
        <package>react: ^19.2.1</package>
        <package>react-dom: ^19.2.1</package>
        <package>@hookform/resolvers: ^5.2.2</package>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-alert-dialog: ^1.1.15</package>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-label: ^2.1.8</package>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-slot: ^1.2.4</package>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-tabs: ^1.1.13</package>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-toast: ^1.2.15</package>
        <package>@supabase/supabase-js: ^2.87.1</package>
        <package>@tanstack/react-query: ^5.90.12</package>
        <package>class-variance-authority: ^0.7.1</package>
        <package>clsx: ^2.1.1</package>
        <package>lucide-react: ^0.555.0</package>
        <package>react-hook-form: ^7.68.0</package>
        <package>tailwind-merge: ^3.4.0</package>
        <package>tailwindcss-animate: ^1.0.7</package>
        <devPackage>typescript: ^5.9.3</devPackage>
        <devPackage>eslint: ^9</devPackage>
        <devPackage>jest: ^29.7.0</devPackage>
        <devPackage>playwright: (via package.json, typically devDependency in Next.js)</devPackage>
        <devPackage>tailwindcss: ^4</devPackage>
      </nodejs>
      <python>
        <package>fastapi==0.123.8</package>
        <package>supabase==2.25.0</package>
        <package>google-generativeai==0.8.5</package>
        <package>uvicorn==0.38.0</package>
        <package>python-dotenv==1.2.1</package>
        <package>pydantic==2.12.5</package>
        <package>httpx==0.28.1</package>
        <package>resend==2.19.0</package>
      </python>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Use React Query for managing the API call's loading, error, and success states on the frontend.</constraint>
    <constraint>Backend API endpoint (POST /api/v1/generation) must follow defined API contract standards (versioning, response formats, wrapped data for success).</constraint>
    <constraint>Backend service needs to handle Gemini API integration, including secure management of API keys (via environment variables).</constraint>
    <constraint>Row Level Security (RLS) must be enabled on any new database tables created to store generated cover letters.</constraint>
    <constraint>E2E tests should use `data-testid` attributes for robust element selection and `page.route()` for mocking API responses (Playwright).</constraint>
  </constraints>
  <interfaces>
    <interface>
      <name>Generate Cover Letter API</name>
      <kind>REST endpoint</kind>
      <signature>POST /api/v1/generation</signature>
      <path>backend/app/api/v1/generation.py</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>Gemini API</name>
      <kind>Third-party API</kind>
      <signature>N/A (external service)</signature>
      <path>N/A</path>
    </interface>
  </interfaces>
  <tests>
    <standards>
      <p>Unit/Component Tests: Jest (Frontend). End-to-End Tests: Playwright (Frontend). E2E tests should use `data-testid` attributes for robust element selection and `page.route()` for mocking API responses. Backend tests are expected to use Pytest.</p>
    </standards>
    <locations>
      <location>frontend/__tests__/</location>
      <location>frontend/playwright/</location>
      <location>backend/tests/</location>
    </locations>
    <ideas>
      <idea ac_id="1">Verify input fields are disabled when the "Generate" button is clicked.</idea>
      <idea ac_id="2">Verify the "Generation Status Indicator" component is displayed during the generation process.</idea>
      <idea ac_id="3">Backend unit/integration test: Mock Gemini API call and verify `POST /api/v1/generation` successfully calls it and returns the result.</idea>
      <idea ac_id="4">Frontend E2E test: Mock `POST /api/v1/generation` response and verify generated cover letter text is displayed correctly on the UI.</idea>
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>
